Hi everyone, I'm Ajit
from Dito Insurance. Today we'll
cover two interesting topics.
First, health insurance
premiums increase every year.  But today, let's look at
how to reduce the impact of premium hikes on us
and how to lock in premiums for a few years
.  Along with that, let's also compare the Hefc Ergo Optima
Secure vs. Optima Super Secure
plans.  So
let's dive into the video. First of all,
something we all need to know is that
health insurance premiums tend to increase during renewal times
.  But
what are the reasons for that? First, medical
inflation, so treatment charges,
equipment costs, all increase every year
.  For example,
doctor consultation charges or surgery
costs are not what they were 20 years ago, but
there is a big difference.  So to cover this increasing medical cost,
insurance companies
also increase premiums every
year, especially as
medical inflation is high in India these days
.  So if it's around 10% per year, we'll have
record medical inflation.  So
there is also a chance that this will impact our premiums.  The second thing is
age, so depending on age, premiums in our policy
may increase every two to four years.  Otherwise, some policies may
also follow age brackets.  So,
in insurance plans, we have an age bracket up
front, from 18 to 35 or 36 to 40 years
.  So
whenever this age bracket changes for us, our
premiums will hike by around 15 to 30%
.  Third one is insurer
stability.  So this is not very common
.  But sometimes, insurance
companies can increase premiums by
obtaining approval from IRDI to maintain profitability
.  So,
there is a chance that our premiums will increase almost every year.
Considering all these factors, it is definitely worth considering whether there is an option to
lock in our premiums for a few years
.
Multi-year plans mean that you
can pay premiums for two or three years at once, rather than paying premiums for one year.  So
what are the benefits of paying like this? The first thing is that we are
given advance discounts.  So if
we pay for two years, we get a 7.5%
discount and if we pay for three years, we
get a 10% discount.
Along with that, the premiums are also fixed.   This
means that if I pay the premiums for the next few years all at once,
even if I have a medical infection, my premiums will not
increase and we will not have the tension of having to renew every year
.  But it
also has its drawbacks.  The first drawback is that you have to
make a one-time big payment
.  The second drawback is that
there is no flexibility.  We
will stay on the same policy for three years.  So it is better to take a
good comprehensive health insurance
policy from a fundamentally strong company
if we want to
pay premiums for the next two or three years at once.
So before making a decision, we should plan
according to our requirements and budget
.  Now coming to the second
part of the video Optima Secure
vs. Optima Super Secure, so
now let's take a look at these two comprehensive
plans.  Sohefc Optima
Secure and Super Secure, as the name
suggests, are two policies that come to us from the HDFC stable
.  So there
are many similarities. For
example, in these policies, we don't have any
restrictions like co-payment, there are no
room rent restrictions, there are no
sub-limits, there are no such restrictions, and the
insurance company pays up to 100% of medical expenses
.  Along with that, we are also provided with pre- and
post-hospitalization coverage
for 60 and 180 days respectively.
Both plans
also provide bonuses, with a 50% bonus every
year up to 100% bonus
.  And the registration
benefit is also provided once per
year by default.  So even if we
use up the cover amount,
we will be given a refill of the cover amount again in the same year
.  And by default
there is also consumables coverage.  So
for example, consumables like cotton, PPE kits, and
sanitizers are also
covered by default in health insurance
.  But even among these similarities, there are
some differences.  The
main difference is that Optima Secure
provides us with 2x coverage
.  This means that if I
take a cover amount of 10 locks, I will be
provided with 20 locks of coverage from day one
.  And
if you look at Optima Super Secure, they are providing 3x coverage
.  So if I take the same 10 lock cover amount
in Optima Super Secure,
I will get 30 locks covered from day one
.  So with bonus, I will have
lakhs base cover, 10 lakhs secure
benefit and 10 lakhs bonus after two years in Optima Secure.
In the same Super Secure, there is a
base cover amount of 10 lakhs, a bonus of 10 lakhs and a
secure benefit of 20 lakhs.  So
Optima Super Secure gives us a little
extra peace of mind.
Otherwise, we
have premium payment flexibility in Optima Secure.  So for
example, if I want to pay premiums for one year,
or for two years, or for three years,
we are given options like this.  So if we
pay premiums for two years,
we get a 7.5% discount on the
overall premium and if we pay for three years,
we get a 10% discount on the
overall premium, but
we don't have this kind of flexibility in Super Secure.  If
we want to take the Super Secure plan,
we will have to pay directly for three years
.  So
in Optima Super Secure, we have a one-time big
payment, but the
premiums remain the same for three years.  So what do
you prefer in your health insurance:
flexibility or an overall
higher cover amount?  So you can also let us know
in the comment section.  So the final
suggestions from our side are that if you
want long-term peace of mind
with higher coverage and an upfront
payment, you can select Super Secure
.  But if you want a
manageable budget and flexibility, you can
select Optima Secure
.  Both are excellent policies.
So, make a decision based on your requirements, budget, and
future goals
.  But if you still have
doubts about health insurance policies, don't worry,
book a free call with Dito. Our
IRDI certified advisors will explain
health insurance to you in simple language
.  The link
is in the description and if you
find this video helpful please like
and share and subscribe to Dito
Insurance for more such informative
videos I am Ajith Signing of Stay
Smart Stay Insured